柯林斯在三分线弧顶对攻着金
Collins working on King here, top of the key-
在他附近带球  过人  起跳
dribbling around him, coming around the corner there, he's up.!
两分进球  漂亮
Two points.! Beautiful play.
动作真漂亮
Now, that's a great play.
你出庭作证的话  没人能保护得住你
If you testify, no one can protect you,
尤其是联邦调查局
especially the feds.
我们会保护你安全的  乔伊
We'll keep you safe, Joey.
对  加入证人保护计划里
Right. In Witness Protection.
这就是他们给你的美好新生活吗
This great new life he's giving you?
你在某个偏远小城的便利店里买东西时
You're sackin' groceries at some goat-town Stop and Shop,
然后维塔尔爪牙过来  朝你后脑勺来两枪
when one of Vitale's guys comes and puts two in the back of your skull.
律师  你在建议证人
Counselor, are you advising a witness
向联邦陪审团隐瞒证据吗
to withhold evidence from a federal grand jury?
他来找的你们  他是自愿的
He came forward. He volunteered.
我建议他在我确保你们有能力保护他前不要作证
I'm advising him not to testify until I'm satisfied you can protect him.
你们能等会再争论吗  我可下了球赛的赌注
Hey, you guys mind? I got money on this.
你还要怎样  我们满足了你一切的要求
What do you want? We gave you everything you asked for.
-我想要意大利面  -你有牛排了  享用吧
- I asked for pasta. - You got steak. Enjoy it.
-你在干什么  -啥
- What are you doin'? - What?
你的戒烟糖呢  我刚给过你一包
Where's your quit candy? I just gave you a pack.
不好意思  我忘了
Yeah, sorry. I forgot.
乔伊  无论他们给我们什么  跟你说什么
Joey, whatever they give us, what they tell you,
要是你发生了意外我能怎么办呢  告他们吗
you get popped, what am I gonna do, sue them?
这不是事情的意义所在
That's not what this is about.
你会怀念我的
You're gonna miss me.
-乔伊  我是你的律师  -你是我的弟弟
- I'm your lawyer, Joey. - You're my brother.
我要做这个  加入证人保护计划
And I do this-you know, I go into Witness Protection-
我们从此不再相见
we're never gonna see each other again.
-你难道不为此烦恼吗  -痛不欲生啊
- That doesn't bother you? - It kills me.
他进攻了  漂亮的挡拆
There he goes. Nice pick.
我要去小解一下
I gotta take a leak.
你还好吗
You all right?
是  没事  就是  有点头晕
Yeah, yeah. Just, uh, a little dizzy.
-去透透气  -好热
- Get some air. - Hot.
-乔伊  -你跟他说了什么
- Joey. - What'd you say to him?
-干得不错  把他带走  -放开我
- Yeah, nice try. Come on! - Let go of me!
-放开我  看不出他病了吗  -乔伊
- Let go of me! Can't you see he's sick? - Joey!
放开我  他有点不对劲
Let me go.! Something's wrong with him.!
乔伊  你别想就这么容易逃过一切
You're not getting out of this that easy. Joey.
你要么死翘翘  要么就出庭作证
Either you're dead or you're testifying.
没有
Don't have it.
-预算报告呢  -没有
- Budget? - Nope.
财务收益表  支出清单
Revenue statement. List of expenses.
豪斯一直都很忙
House has been very busy.
拯救新泽西洲免于麻风病吗  这个我明白
Saving New Jersey from leprosy. Yes, I know.
把他的所创造的效益告诉我  是你的工作
Getting me his numbers, that's your job.
-我们正在开会  -我需要个律师
- We're in a meeting. - I need the lawyer.
你整死了哪个病人
Who'd you kill?
目前没有  不过现在还没到午餐时间
Nobody. But it's not even lunch.
我接到联邦法庭的指令
I got served with a federal court order.
一个证人陷入昏迷
Some witness went into a coma.
他们要我去看一下
They want me to take a look at him.
什么
What?
他们要你去检查一个病人吗
They want you to examine a sick person?
这简直是公关的恶梦
This is a public relations nightmare.
人们知道我们这儿的医生收治这类病人的话
Folk think our staff do that kind of thing around here,
这里就会爬满了病人
this place will be crawling with sick people.
我是个医生  不是联调局的小狗  不玩接飞盘
I'm a doctor. I'm not a lapdog for the feds. I don't play fetch.
没人能驾驭的了你  我说得对吗  卡迪医生
Nobody tells you what to do. Am I right, Dr. Cuddy?
眼下你有三条路  雇律师请求法院收回法令
You have three choices. Hire a lawyer to fight the order,
要么治疗他  或者藐视律令直接坐牢
treat the guy or go to jail for contempt.
自己选吧
Up to you.
蹲监狱  正合你意  又不是小女生
Jail. You'd like that. No more naughty schoolgirl.
她的新幻想  夫妻探监
Conjugal visit- that's her new fantasy.
他不走我们是不会走的  除非
We're not leaving until he's gone, or you show me...
你能至少给一个我们留下他的理由
one good reason for keeping him.
他完全失去知觉了啊
He's really out of it, huh?
昏迷的原因有新陈代谢  构造问题
Causes of coma- metabolic, structural
他洗过胃了
He had his stomach pumped.
-他们为什么这么做  -排除中毒的因素
- Why would they do that? - Rule out poisoning.
第一反应通常不是下毒啊
Huh. Not the typical first guess.
不  他们的第一猜测是他装假
Nope, first guess was faking it.
我猜病人可能不情愿做联邦调查局的证人
The patient's a federal witness- reluctant, I'm assuming.
他的格拉斯昏迷指数为8
He's also an eight on the Glasgow Coma Scale.
奄奄一息  这挺难装的啊
He's barely alive. Pretty tough to fake.
最近头部受过伤吗  发生车祸或者不慎跌倒
Any recent history of head trauma? Bad car accident? Fall?
他们说没有  不过做个核磁共振以防万一
They tell me no, but do an M.R.I. to be sure.
新陈代谢引起肝肾功能紊乱  糖尿病
Metabolic causes- liver, kidney, diabetes-
都做一遍吧  反正是政府买单
Check for everything. Feds are paying.
孩子们  我们这次能大赚一笔
We're gonna turn a profit on this one, boys.
豪斯医生  我是比尔·阿奈罗
Dr. House, Bill Arnello.
我是史密斯先生的律师
I'm a lawyer.I represent Mr. Smith.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
我有带着这么多问题去烦过你吗
Do I come to you with my problems?
他也是我哥哥
He's also my brother.
什么  你改姓了啊
What? You changed your name?
史密斯这个姓不够体面吗
Smith wasn't good enough for you?
他叫乔伊  是我唯一的哥哥
His name's Joey. He's my only brother.
懂了  他对你至关重要
He's important to you. Got it.
不会给他用安慰剂的  我们会用真药
So, no placebos for him. We'll use the real medicine.
跟你聊天真有趣  等会儿再聊
This was fun. Let's do it again soon.
你哥竟然是黑手党
Brother in the Mafia?
你就称呼他乔伊吗
So, just Joey?
还以为会有个昵称呢
I was hoping for a nickname.
芒果乔伊  扳手乔伊之类
Joey Mango. Joey the Wrench.
大家都知道我在哪
People know where I am.
希望你能尽心尽力
I want you to do your job.
找出他的病因  治好他  然后把他留在这
Diagnose him, fix him and keep him here.
我们有点类似专科医院
We're a bit of a specialized hospital.
通常只接受那些真正生病的人
We generally only deal with patients while they're actually sick.
如果你把我哥交由政府
If you release my brother to the government,
他按他们说的做了
and he does what they want,
即便你治好他  他还是难逃一死
even if you fix him, he's dead.
我需要时间说服他
I need time to convince him of that.
好消息是  如果你搞砸了
Good news is, if you screw up,
我们不会因医疗事故而起诉你
you don't have to worry about a malpractice suit.
我会一件一件夺走你的心爱之物
Instead, one by one,
直到你一无所有
I'll take away the things you love till there's nothing left.
那你们真的是黑手党咯
So, on the Mafia thing, that's a yes.
你觉得豪斯是不是有点古怪啊
Did House seem weird to you?
他觉得他还不够古怪吗
Were you expecting him to be weird?
我们坦白了互相的感觉
We spoke... about how we felt.
-你向他表白了吗  -当然没有
- You told him you liked him? - No, of course not.
那你们说了些什么
Wh-What are you talking about then?
我问他是否喜欢我
I asked him if he liked me.
为什么这么做
Why would you do that?
因为...我喜欢他
Because- I like him.
你说的喜欢是那种喜欢吗
You like him like him?
无所谓了  反正他不喜欢我
Doesn't matter. He doesn't like me.
他谁也不喜欢
Hey, he doesn't like anybody.
也没人喜欢他
And nobody likes him.
核磁共振结果表明他的硬膜下血肿
M.R.I. Showed a subdural hematoma.
出血导致他的颅内压升高
Bleeding around his brain caused pressure inside his head,
从而引起昏迷
which caused the coma.
看上去像伪膜
These look like pseudo-membranes.
短期内无法形成
Those take time to form.
如果是旧伤  不会引起昏迷
If it's an old injury, it wouldn't cause the coma.
病历上记载他在1996年被轮胎撬棍打伤过
Patient history indicates he was hit with a tire iron in 1996.
他弟说他在换轮胎时  撬棍不慎弹到了头上
Brother says he was changing a tire and it slipped.
位于所见之处的旧血肿或许能导致他的昏迷
An old hematoma placed where this one is could have caused his coma.
-肝情况怎么样  -肝功能检测结果略偏高
- What about his liver? - L.F.T.'s are slightly elevated.
略微高而已  但不足以引发昏迷
Key word is "Slightly," As in not high enough to cause the coma.
是硬膜下血肿的问题
It's the subdural.
要我说就清除血肿  看他是否会醒
I say we evacuate the cavity, see if he wakes up.
神经科医生认为病因在他的脑部
The neurologist thinks it's his brain
要对他施行开颅  我深感震惊
and wants to open up his head? Frankly, I'm shocked.
你得用老爸红色工具箱里"大块头"专用钻头
And you get to use the "Big boy" Drill in Daddy's big red toolbox.
不用钻头
No drilling.
-大家好  -史密斯先生
- Hi. - Mr. Smith.
叫我乔伊就行  能不能别那样啊
Call me Joe. Can you not do that?
都听清楚我说不要钻头了吧
So, we're clear about the no drilling?
他没事了  可以出院了
He's okay now. He can leave.
我不会放他出院的
I'm not releasing him.
就因为他弟弟不愿意吗
'Cause the brother doesn't want you to?
是因为他的昏迷病因不明  哪个理由顺耳些
Or because he had an unexplained coma. Which sounds better?
血肿引发了昏迷
The hematoma caused the coma.
这个诊断真是悦耳  你都可以随其起舞了
That's a catchy diagnosis. You could dance to that.
我赞同奇斯的看法
I think Chase is right.
血肿仍需清除  但非当务之急
It still should be evacuated, but it's not an immediate threat.
卡梅隆定合我心
Cameron's my girl.
我会让他出院
I'd release him.
你不赞同我是不是因为...
Are you disagreeing with me because-
这是我的专业医疗意见
I'm disagreeing because that's my medical opinion.
当然是啊
Of course it is.
除非我被提名为"邪恶轴心"的第四成员
But unless I've been named as the fourth part of the "Axis of evil,"
语出小布什著名演讲
明确指示的国家有伊朗  伊拉克和朝鲜
被入侵占领了  否则这里还是我说了算
invaded and occupied, this is still not a democracy.
他继续留院
He's staying.
去做一下肝炎血清学和自身免疫性疾病筛查
Send for hepatitis serologies and an autoimmune panel.
我和你一样
Hey, I'm with you.
到了可以喝酒做蠢事的年纪
Old enough to drink, old enough to do something really stupid
再生个孩子
and make yourself a baby.
他是我弟
He's my brother.
我父母去了巴巴多斯  我暂时照看他而已
I'm watching him while our parents are in Barbados.
他呼吸困难  到处都能听到干啰音
He's having trouble breathing, and there's a lot of wheezing.
确切的说是哮鸣音  上呼吸道和鼻部都能听到
Whistling, technically. Upper airways. Nose.
如果他得了哮吼
If he's got the croup,
-会演变成脑膜炎  是吗  -当然
- that, that could become meningitis, right? - Absolutely.
当时我在学习
I- I was just studying,
突然间他哭了  哭声很怪异
and all of a sudden I hear him crying and sounding all weird.
我父母会杀了我的
Oh- M-My parents are gonna kill me.
-我不相信  -你不了解他们
- I doubt it. - You don't know them.
我是说你爸妈不在的时候你会学习
No, I doubt you were studying while your parents were away.
长官  你好
Hello, Officer.
你会洗洗再让他玩的吧
You might wanna rinse this off before you let him play with it again.
怎么了  他在哪儿
What happened? Where is he?
沃格勒找到了住院处  住院处叫了司法机构
Vogler called Admitting. Admitting called Justice.
司法机构来把他带走了
Justice came and took him away.
那谁给沃格勒报信的
And who called Vogler?
他是个赔钱货
He loses money.
眼科也在赔钱  管他呢  这是所医院
So does Ophthalmology. Who cares? This is a hospital.
-你不能撤掉一个部门  -你无法驾驭他
- You can't just cut a department. - You can't control him.
只有我才"能"驾驭他
I am the only one that can control him.
说说说说曹操  曹操就到
D-D-Dr. House in the house
你总是出现得很及时嘛
Impeccable timing as always.
你无权放走我的病人
You had no authority to release my patient.
我的同事刚跟我说她有项独一无二的才能
My colleague has just informed me she has a singular talent.
正好你来证明一下
You are just in time for a demonstration.
豪斯医生  据我所知
Dr. House, from what I understand,
-你的病人...  -你从何得知
- your patient - From what you understand,
他又不是你的病人
he's not your patient.
-你能知道什么啊  -悲哀啊
- How the hell do you understand anything? - It's sad.
你连医生都算不上
You're not even a doctor.
只因法院命令  他才得以在此治疗
John Smith is here only because of a court order.
我把病历传真给了法官  她撤销了法令
I had the records faxed to the judge. She rescinded the order.
你大费周章  就是想惹恼我吗
Why bother? Just to piss me off?
不想趟政府的浑水
Keeping the government off our ass.
-对公共机构没啥好处  -好吧
- That makes no sense for a public institution. - Okay.
-什么好吧  -长官  好的
- Okay, what? - Okay, sir.
你们继续
Carry on.
他真的关心病人
He really cares about his patients.
他一无所获就出去了  肯定有事发生
Yeah, and he just walked out of here with nothin'. Something's up.
他开始呕吐  继而昏迷
Just started vomiting and passed out.
再上点利多卡因和肾上腺素
More lidocaine. 590, with epi.
35岁男性
Thirty-five year old male
生命体征稳定  在路上给他补充了两升生理盐水
Vital signs are stable now. Gave him two liters en route.
他两小时前刚出院
He was just released from here two hours ago.
你说他已恢复  可以走了
You said he was good to go.
-注意那条管子  -他还是没有反应
- Watch that line. - He's still not responding.
联邦调查局的新人奖章也不是那么好看的哦
So, the junior G-man badge isn't looking so good.
-他的肝脏恶化了  -昏迷吗
- His liver's worse. - Comatose?
不  与先前一次症状完全不同
No. Completely different symptoms than the first time.
血清学检验丙肝阳性
His serology tests came back positive for hepatitis "C."
丙肝是慢性病
Hep "C" Is a chronic condition.
你觉得这不是急性病吗
You don't think this is an acute situation?
昏迷  呕吐  腹痛  一切症状都指向丙肝
Coma, vomiting, abdominal pain. Hep "C" Explains everything.
那怎么解释突然发作
Except for the suddenness of the onset.
时间怎么了
What's wrong with the timing?
某天晚上回到家中
You get home one night,
你被你老婆用棒球棍打了一棒
your wife hits you with a baseball bat.
可能是因为
Likely causes:
8年来你不曾感谢过她为你煮晚饭
The fact that you haven't thanked her for dinner in eight years...
或者在你裤子找到了皮手铐的发票[SM工具]
or the receipt for fur handcuffs that she found in your pants?
突发和事先计划  其结果都是一样的
Sudden onset equals approximate cause.
他血液里的雌性激素也偏高
He also has high estrogen levels in his blood.
这也是支持慢性病的一项指标  而非急性病
That's indicative of a chronic condition, not acute.
仅一项指标  其它肝功指标怎样
One test. What do his other liver tests tell us?
白蛋白水平正常  说明是急性发作
Normal albumen levels point toward acute.
怎么?  她的检查结果就比我的可信吗
Oh, okay, and, uh, why is her test better than mine?
尽管你们的结果相差无几  但是她更可爱
Because she's cuter, though it's close.
做个肝脏活检  结果出来时
Do a liver biopsy. When the results come back,
我们就知道病因了
we'll know what we're looking at.
为什么不治疗丙肝
Why wait to treat the hep "C"?
如果我说对了  那么乔伊就能尽早恢复
If I'm right, Joey gets better that much faster.
对的  然后他去出庭作证
Right. Then he gets to testify.
你就能从卡迪那里得个大红花
And you get a gold star from Cuddy.
那有什么不好  或者说这就是不好
And what's the downside? Or is that the downside?
不想让你得红花  还需要理由吗
Do I have a reason for not wanting you to get any stars?
好吧  开始治疗
Fine. Start the treatment.
你全权负责  别提我的名字
It's all your idea. Don't even mention my name.
你的理论没漏洞  开工吧
There's nothing wrong with your theory. Go.
但是当你还在"供我取乐"部门时
But in the "Humor me" Department,
你就得听我的  顺便去做个活检
get a biopsy while you're at it.
福曼  我们要谈谈
Foreman, we need to talk.
-这个病人你不用管了  -什么
- You're off the case. - What?
为什么
Why?
有人向沃格勒告密
Somebody told Vogler
说我欺骗了肝脏移植协会
that I lied to the transplant committee.
-你认为我是告密者吗  -你谨小慎微
- You think I did? - You're too careful.
没有十足把握  是不会轻举妄动的
You wouldn't jump ship unless you knew what was in the water.
别说了  你在羞辱我
Stop. You're embarrassing me.
可我想沃格勒认为我把你当做告密者
But I want Vogler to think I think it's you.
而我要卡梅隆和奇斯
And I want Cameron and Chase,
卡迪和威尔森  护士们
Cuddy and Wilson, the nursing staff...
甚至停车场的收费员都这么认为
and the cashier in the parking lot to think that too.
好吧
Right.
血检表明你得了丙肝
The blood tests show you have hepatitis "C."
这种病毒会感染肝脏
It's a virus that infects the liver.
不可能
No way.
未必是个坏消息啊
It's not all bad news.
这种病通常是可医治的
It can often be cured.
即便无法治愈  也是药物可控制的
And even if not, it's manageable.
我哥怎么染上这病的
How'd my brother get this?
该病通常通过体液交换传染  要么...
It usually involves the exchange of bodily fluids. Either-
体液  你什么意思
Bodily fluids? What are you talkin' about?
病毒传染的途径很多
There are many ways the virus can be transmitted-
比如说共用注射针头  输血
sharing needles, blood transfusions-
注意点  没人敢这么跟我哥说话
Hey! Nobody talks to my brother like this, okay?
好  不知道他怎么染上这病的
Fine. No idea how he got it.
可他身上携带丙肝病毒  我们要给他用...
But he has hepatitis "C." We're gonna start him on-
他没有染上丙肝  以后把嘴给我闭紧了
He doesn't have it. Don't mention it again.
别以丙肝治疗
Don't treat him for it.
豪斯有一些直接捐赠人以及基金会的赞助
House has some directed donations, foundation support-
在这里
It's around here.
他让你苦不堪言
He makes you miserable.
他在这里工作8年  一个子儿都没赚
Eight years he's worked here- never made a dime for you.
-从不听命于你  -他会变的  他
- Never listened to you. - He can change. He's-
8年了  他都没变
He hasn't changed in eight years.
要么是他不会改变  要么就是你无力改变他
Either he can't change, or you can't change him.
你自己都数不清他骗了你多少次
You have no idea how many times he's lied to you,
蔑视你的权威
undercut your authority,
让你在其它医生面前颜面尽失
made you look like crap to other doctors.
是  我恨他
Yes, I hate him,
而我现在却拼命想保住他的饭碗
and here I am desperately trying to protect his job.
-你对此作何解释  -说明你不恨他
- What does that tell you? - That you don't hate him.
我不是在保护自己喜欢的人
I do not protect people I like.
我是保护医院的人才资源
I protect people who are assets to this hospital.
不  那是我的行事风格
No. That's me.
而你
You-
-而你太软弱  -好吧
- You're softer. - Right.
美国的主要医疗机构里
There are three female chiefs of medicine...
一共只有三名女性主管
at major hospitals in this country,
我们都是通过我们女性手腕坐到这个位子的
and we all got there using our feminine wiles.
保护自己喜欢的人乃人之常情
It's human nature to want to protect people we like.
我不喜欢他
I don't like him.
你想如果我们能组成合适的团队
To think if we just form the right team,
我们就能融洽相处  同舟共济
we'll all get along and be able to pull the boat-
-我跟他相处不融洽  -这不是一个团队
- I don't get along with him! - This is not a team.
这不是一艘船  也不是一个机器
It's not a boat. It's not a machine
无需众多零件共同合作
that has a lot of parts that have to work together.
比喻都是废话
The metaphors are all crap.
说白了这就是生意  仅此而已
This is a business. That's all it is.
你喜欢他  有损商业利益
You like him. That's bad for business.
都是我的错
Oh, this is all my fault.
又借着做作业休息的名义去偷玩了吗
Took another homework break with Betty Lou?
不是  上周我表演了一个魔术
No, last week I showed him a magic trick.
你从他鼻子里拿出了一枚25分硬币  经典啊
You pulled a quarter out of his nose. It's a classic.
是啊  可他现在不停的往那塞东西
Yeah, and now he won't stop shovin' stuff up there.
-豪斯医生  -这里有紧急事件
- Dr. House. - Got a crisis here.
没事的
It's okay.
别闹了
Stop!
你这招倒是简单利落
That's a neat trick.
你得让孩子们相信你真的会打他们
They have to believe you'll actually hurt them.
你的手下侮辱我哥
Your people insulted my brother.
把罗马诺干酪放进帕尔马干酪罐里去了吗
What, they put Romano in the Parmesan cheese shaker again?
说他是瘾君子  同性恋啊  诸如此类
Said he was a crackhead or a homo or somethin'.
那些傻瓜
Those idiots.
得送他们去培训多少次情商啊
How many times am I gonna have to send them for sensitivity training?
没人说他是同性恋  情节太恶劣了
Nobody's saying he's a homo. That would be really, really bad.
换个友好的说法
So let's put a nice, friendly spin on it.
譬如  "他在监狱里被强奸了"
Let's go with, "He got raped in prison."
我看到监狱纹身了
I saw the jailhouse tats.
将之与血检结果联想在一起
Put it together with the blood tests.
是有谣言  可乔伊一直避而不谈
There were rumors, but Joey never said anything about it.
如果被人发现他得了丙肝
If people find out he's bein' treated for hep "C"-
联邦调查局得到那个病历
Feds get that chart,
一传十  十传百
someone says somethin' to somebody, word will get out.
那么乔伊的地位名声将会毁于一旦
And then Joey's manhood, his rep- he's destroyed.
你是担心
You're worried about
他在得梅因市沃尔玛的同事的反应
how his coworkers will react at the Wal-Mart in Des Moines.
他不会加入证人保护计划的
He's not going into Witness Protection.
我不会让此发生的
I'm not gonna let that happen.
听着  我不知道你知不知道
Listen, I don't know if you know about this,
黑社会一般都有两本帐簿
but mob businesses sometimes keep two sets of books.
-一个合法  一个非法  -没错
- One legit, one not. - Exactly.
你逗我玩吗
You jerkin' my chain?
医生们很忙的
Doctors are busy.
他们偶尔会忘了记下一些东西  这种事很常见的
Sometimes they forget to write things down. Happens all the time.
谢谢
Thanks.
还有
Oh, and, uh,
你给他的药
whatever you're not giving him for whatever he doesn't have,
会治好他吗
is that gonna fix him?
不一定
I doubt it.
打算给沃格勒的车抛光吗
On your way to polish Vogler's car?
脾气暴躁的老医生在地下室替病人看病
Gone are the days of the grumpy old doc.seeing patients
拿几只鸡当医药费
in the basement of his house,
那种日子早已远去
getting paid a few chickens.
怎么吃
How will I eat?
你知道沃格勒整整两天都在卡迪的办公室
You know what Cuddy's been locked away with Vogler about...
大门不出  二门不迈吗
all day today and yesterday?
地板蜡的价格飞涨吗
Floor polish costs through the roof?
因为你
You.
昨天卡迪的秘书一整天都在复印你的资料
Her secretary's been at the photocopier all day with your records.
他们现在就在看里面看资料
That's all they're looking at in there.
我的车被偷了
My car's been stolen.
是转世了吧
Or rein-car-nated.
老破车光荣退休
Pink slip.
阿奈罗兄弟赠你的礼物
A gift from the Arnello brothers.
他们是黑帮分子没错
You know, they're gangsters, sure,
但他们也很体贴人呐
but they're thoughtful too.
你不能收下  这是贿赂
You can't keep it. It's... graft.
不  不  才不是
No, no, no, no. Uh-uh.
贿赂应该是
Graft is if I tell him
我先威胁不给票子就不治好他
I'll only make him better if he slips me a couple bucks.
或者买通我做不该做的事
Or a payoff for something I'm not supposed to do.
前提是我伸手要好处  可我并没有
If I'd asked for the payoff, which I didn't,
给不给反正我都要干坏事的
I would've done the bad thing anyway.
所以这没有问题
So there's nothing wrong with this.
-对噢  -帅啊
- Right. - Damn.
65款
Sixty-five.
保存完美
Perfectly restored.
你说要是有人拒绝乔伊的礼物
What do you think a guy like Joey would do
他那种人会怎么做
if someone turned down a gift?
这算是侮辱他了  对吧
That's kind of an insult, isn't it?
他可能会伤害你  绝对有可能
He might hurt you. It's definitely possible.
我完了  没得选  必须收下这车
I'm screwed. Gotta take the car.
看到豪斯的新车了没
Did you see House's new car?
乔伊送的  显然他不能接受
From Joey. He obviously can't keep it.
医院从沃格勒那儿拿钱你就不介意了
You don't mind the hospital taking money from Vogler?
这不一样  沃格勒是合法投资
That's different. Vogler's legit.
这更糟糕  沃格勒投钱是带着一堆条件的
That's worse. Vogler's money came with strings.
沃格勒不会诓我  害我被黑道的人打
Vogler doesn't set me up to have a mobster take a swing at me.
-我相信豪斯不知情  -乔伊血压下降了
- I'm sure House didn't know- - Joey's pressure dropped.
静脉输液之后  收缩压维持在100毫米汞柱
Pushed I.V. fluids, now he's holding a hundred systolic.
-败血症吗  -不  他好像肝脏内出血
- Septic? - No, it looks like he's bleeding into his liver.
是静脉曲张  慢性丙肝通常会这样
Varices. See it with chronic hep "C" all the time.
活检报告来了
Biopsy's back.
两大发现  第一
Two findings. Number one,
淋巴细胞性浸润  而桥接纤维化
lymphocytic infiltrate and no bridging fibrosis.
看来要他命的病不是丙肝  是急性的
Whatever's killing him's not hep "C." It's acute.
这话谁说过来着  我忘了
Who said that? I forget.
你在这儿干嘛  我告诉过你退出这个病例
What are you doing here? I told you you were off the case.
对  你用魔鬼计谋
Right. Your diabolic plan
去让邪恶告密者相信他已经安全了
to convince the evil genius he's in the clear,
于是他就会放松警惕露出马脚  你聪明
so he'll let his guard down and make a fatal mistake. Sure.
哎呀  你一说明显没用了嘛现在
Well, it's clearly not gonna work now.
什么邪恶告密者
What evil genius?
我们知道的话  就用不着魔鬼计谋了  是吧
If we knew that, we wouldn't need a diabolic plan, would we?
豪斯认为有人向沃格勒告密出卖他
House thinks someone ratted him out to Vogler.
什么  我们吗
What, one of us?
不  你们太爱我了
No, you guys love me too much.
行了  如果不是丙肝
Look, if it's not the hep "C,"
那是什么问题  引起肝衰竭
Then what's the problem? What's causing the liver failure?
第二大发现  毒素
Finding number two, toxins.
不会  他才30岁
No. He's only 30 years old,
他的职业也没有接触重金属  或是环境中...
and his job doesn't expose him to heavy metals or environmental-
他是30岁的黑帮分子
He's a 30-year-old mobster.
他的职业不会让他意外暴露在毒素中
He doesn't have a job that results in accidental exposure to toxins.
但会使他被人故意暴露在毒素里
He has a job that results in intentional exposure to toxins.
有人给他下了毒
Someone's poisoned him.
不管是什么毒  毒性发挥很快
Whatever this toxin is, it's doing the job and fast.
还有多久才能拿到下一轮检查结果
How long till we have the next round of test results?
四个钟头左右吧
About four hours.
可惜他的肝脏只能再坚持两个小时
Too bad his liver's only gonna last another two.
我们必须给他换肝
We're gonna have to get him a new one.
你说笑  两小时内
What, in two hours?
还有个办法
There is another way.
放心  符合犹太教规矩
Relax. It's kosher.
这太诡异了
This is so bizarre.
也不是  我们只不过把乔伊的血从他体内抽出来
Not really. We just take Joey's blood out of his body...
打进猪身体里过一遍
and run it through a pig.
猪的肝脏可以代替乔伊衰竭的肝  清洗血液
The pig's liver does what Joey's can't. It cleans the blood.
然后再把血送回乔伊体内
Which we send right back to him.
猪能帮他治病?
And the pig makes him better?
不  只能帮我们争取时间
Nope. Just buys us some time
来查明你弟弟中的什么毒
to figure out what's poisoning your brother.
说的轻松  好像你们天天都这么给人看病
Like nothin'. Like you do this all the time.
噢  其实我们地下室有个牲畜棚
Oh, we've basically got a barn in the basement.
排除毒芹
Cross off hemlock.
你以为是毒芹
You thought he was being poisoned by hemlock?
欧里庇得斯[希腊悲剧大师]叫你查的
Dr. Euripides tell you to check for that?
这儿的高速公路旁边长了很多
It grows wild by the highways out here.
说说  你有多喜欢豪斯
So, how much do you like House?
-奇斯真是大嘴巴  -是啊
- Chase has a big mouth. - Yeah.
说不定就是他向沃格勒告密
He's probably the one who ratted to Vogler.
我觉得他不会...
I don't think that he would--
和豪斯在一起时痛苦吗
Does it hurt when you're with House?
好像肚子隐隐作痛  但又感觉很好
Little pain in the tummy, but it sort of feels good too?
我没权力喜欢上别人吗
I don't have the right to show interest in someone?
你当然有
You absolutely do.
而我也有绝对的权利拿这个来嘲笑你
And I absolutely have the right to humiliate you for it.
有发现吗
Anything?
白血球计数低  应该是因为生病
White blood count's low, probably a result of the illness.
和肝脏无关
Nothing to connect to the liver.
-他吸烟吗  -我查查看
- Is he a smoker? - Let me check.
肺气肿的早期症状
Early signs of emphysema.
起码抽了十几年了
He's been smoking at least a dozen years.
十八年  你从白血球计数看出来的
Eighteen. You got that from the white count?
不是  从胸部X光片看出来的
Nope. Got that from the chest X-ray.
白血球计数只告诉我他在戒烟
White count just tells me he's quitting.
两周前开始的
Two weeks ago.
你的肚子还好吗
How's your tummy?
平坦紧密
Flat and taut.
我做这行12年了
I've been on the job for 12 years.
你今天早上往你妻子的户头里存了三千美金
You put $3,000 in your wife's checking account this morning.
我要知道这笔钱哪里来的
I wanna know where it came from.
-我的记录向来良好  -钱从哪里来的
- I got a perfect record. - Where did you get the money?
撤下刑具  我找到元凶了
Cancel the thumbscrews. I've got our culprit.
-谁  -不是"谁"  是"胡"
- Who? - Not who, "Hu."
-啊  - 感谢合作
- Huh? - Thanks for playing along.
柴胡  他戒烟糖里有中草药
Chai Hu. Chinese herb in his "Quit smoking" Candy.
减轻烟瘾  同时也减少白血球计数
Reduces cravings. Also reduces his white blood count.
噢对  也是他吃太多  把自己给毒了
Oh, yeah, he also took enough of them to poison himself.
我们会让他在猪身上再多待几小时
We'll keep him on the pig for a few more hours,
然后给他戒了戒烟糖
and then take him off the candy.
他就会好的
He'll be fine.
猪就不好了  真惨
Pig won't be. Oh, no.
嘿
Hey.
感觉好点没
Hey, feelin'better?
饿死我了
I'm famished.
医院菜单上应该有鱼条
I think they got fish sticks on the menu.
是啊  让我怀念起监狱
Ah, yeah. Makes me miss prison.
那么古惑仔可以出院了
So, the mobster's good to go?
我先留他一晚上  然后通知联调局
I'll keep him overnight, then let the feds know...
他可以出去继续作供了
he's good to rat out whoever he wants.
-他弟弟会不高兴  -可能我得把车还回去了
- Brother won't be happy. - Maybe I have to give back the car.
-你应该让沃格勒去和联调局说  -为什么
- You should let Vogler tell the feds. - Why?
因为他在意这件事
Because it matters to him.
因为乔伊第一次出院时  你出了他的丑
Because you humiliated him the first time Joey was released.
我说朋友  你觉得你还应该蹲守三垒吗
You think you should still be in third there, ace?
他是自取其辱
He humiliated himself.
还因为你的工作保不保得住
And because your job depends on the kind of mood
要看沃格勒和卡迪促膝长谈之后的心情
Vogler's in at the end of his marathon with Cuddy.
说真的  大哥
Seriously, man,
你以前有没有开过汽车啊
have you ever actually driven an automobile before?
一共有四档  知不知道
There are four gears, you know?
66款配有一键"闭嘴"按钮
The '66 came with a "Shut up" Button.
我对这些检查有疑问
I have a problem with the tests.
我要知道...
I need to know-
从医学角度出发
It is my medical opinion
我判断病人已经康复  可以出院了
that the patient is healthy and can be released.
谢谢你来告诉我们
Thanks for letting us know.
给我接联邦检察官办公室
Get me the U.S. Attorney's office.
看来你认识到我们开会谈什么了
I see you found out what we're meeting about.
你们在开会呀
You're having a meeting?
随你怎么说  你穿白大褂挺好看
Well, whatever the reason, the coat looks good on you.
柴胡糖造成这么严重的肝衰竭  怎么可能
Chai Hu lozenges cause this kind of liver failure? No way.
柴胡糖本身不会
Not by themselves.
但是结合干扰素  就像是火上浇油
But in combination with the interferon it's like gas to a flame.
-什么干扰素  -治丙肝的
- What interferon? - For the hep "C."
什么丙肝
What hep "C"?
隐瞒黑帮分子的丙肝  很重要吗
Is hiding a mobster's hep "C" that important?
让联调局知道一切实情  就重要吗
Is letting the feds know everything that important?
-你无敌了  就算现在...  -爱德
- You are a piece of work. Even now, knowing- - Ed-
爱德华
Edward.
乔伊又昏迷了
Joey's back in a coma.
情况稳定  但却昏迷
He's stable, but comatose.
比之前更糟  他现在要靠呼吸机
Worse than before. He's on a ventilator.
问题是为什么
Question is, why?
不是大脑  不是中毒
It's not his brain. It's not a toxin.
我们的朋友猪猪帮他清了毒
Our friend Babe helped with that one.
-那么还有什么  -丙肝
- So, what else? - Hep "C."
我们没有真正治疗过这个
We never really treated it.
一出现肝中毒我们就停用干扰素了
We stopped the interferon when it started poisoning his liver.
是不是要我写首歌你才满意  他的慢性丙肝
Am I gonna have to write a song about it? His chronic hep "C'"...
没那么重  不至于产生这些症状
was not bad enough to produce these symptoms.
可雌激素水平表明是这问题
The estrogen level indicates it is.
根本不是一回事
It indicates something else entirely.
我们现在不能给他用干扰素
We can't give him interferon now.
他体内还存留着柴胡糖
There are still traces of the lozenges in his system.
-只会让他再次中毒  -基因
- It'll just poison him again. - Genetics.
我们不治疗病毒  我们改变它
We don't treat the virus, we change it.
有种非核苷类变构酶抑制剂
A non-nucleoside allosteric inhibitor.
从来没在人身上试过  可能会害死他
It's never been tried on a human being. It could kill him.
有区别吗  不用他也死定了
What's the difference? He's dead without it.
费城的圣塞巴斯蒂安医院
They're running a trial... on dogs
正在狗身上做试验
at St. Sebastian's out in Philadelphia.
我打电话问问
I'll make the call.
还有哪种可能会使雌激素这么高
What else could cause his estrogen level to be that high?
没了
Nothing.
我们会把药打在这里
We're gonna put the medicine in here.
防止打进药时刺激静脉
Don't want it to burn his veins when it goes in.
你们根本没把握会有用
And you have no idea if it'll work.
试验阶段疗效很乐观
It's shown promise in testing.
可能里面没有东西  我像老鹰一样盯着他
Ma-Maybe there's nothing up there. I watched him like a hawk.
我敢肯定你没有
Pretty sure you didn't.
我没让他再玩小玩具
I- I didn't let him play with any more little toys.
于是他不得不把大玩具塞进去
Thus forcing him to shove a big one up there.
不许哭  否则我打断你鼻子
Stop, or I snap your nose off!
他不是太聪明的
He- He's not too smart.
遗传的威力很强大
Genetics is a powerful force.
反过来说  也许他比你想象中要聪明
On the other hand, maybe he's smarter than you think.
-怎么了  -等一会儿
- What's goin' on? - Just give me a second.
一直想用用这玩意儿
Always wanted to use one of these.
-把他的头朝后仰  -不要这样吧
- Tilt his head back. - I- I don't know. I do-
把他的头朝后仰
Just tilt his head back.
概念领会得真棒  各种关系
Nice grasp of concepts. Relationships.
很聪明  很酷
Very smart. Very cool.
先是警察  消防员  然后是消防车
First the policeman, the fireman, then the fire truck.
你弟弟派了一队人马去救这只猫
Your brother was sending in teams to save the cat.
有时  最简单的答案...
Sometimes the simplest answer-
哪一种昏迷人会自己醒过来
What types of comas do you just snap out of?
这一次他没醒过来  没有起色
He's not snapping out of this one. He's not improving.
你划掉了雌激素  有解释吗
You've crossed out estrogen. You got an explanation?
有  解释非常简单
Yes, I have, a very simple one.
是什么
And?
保密
It's private.
你认为是我  向沃格勒投诚
You think I'm the one- running to Vogler.
目前你嫌疑最大
You're currently top of the list.
中毒性昏迷
Toxic comas-
只要远离源头时间够久就会恢复
Person's away from the cause long enough, they recover.
联调局检查过毒素  我们也检查过
The feds checked for poisons. We checked for poisons.
不是我告密的
I didn't do it.
-那就不是中毒  -是过敏
- It's not a poison then. - An allergy.
-听到我说的吗  -会不会食物过敏
- Did you hear me? - What about a food sensitivity?
他吃的东西全都是严格管制的
All his food is strictly controlled.
他的饮食和病情并无关联
There's no correlation between his meals and his condition.
第一次昏迷之前  他吃了牛排和土豆
He had steak and potatoes before the first coma,
第二次昏迷之前  吃的是医院的鱼条
and the hospital served fish sticks before the second one.
你可以相信我
You can trust me.
问题是  如果我不能相信你
Problem is, if I can't trust you,
我就不能相信你说的"你可以相信我"
I can't trust your statement that I can trust you.
不过还是谢谢了  你帮了大忙
But thanks anyway. You've been a big help.
-你那钱是哪儿来的  -什么
- So, where did you get the money? - What?
-有人拿钱收买你  -你在胡说什么
- Someone paid you off. - What are you talkin' about?
他不是中毒  你告诉我们的...
He wasn't poisoned. You told us that-
谁在说中毒了  我说的是好处费  贿赂
Who's talking about poison? I'm talking about payoffs, graft.
不要烦他
Leave him alone.
原来是你贿赂了法警
You paid the marshal off.
我没付钱叫他给我弟弟下毒
I didn't pay him to poison my brother.
没有  但结果是这样
No. It just worked out that way.
我给他钱请他弄点好的饭菜进来
I gave the guy some money to bring in some decent food.
比鱼条更好的  我在想牛排
Better than fish sticks? I'm thinking steak.
我们要的是面条  可那些鸟警察才不在乎...
We asked for pasta, but those stupid feds could care less-
他两次昏迷前都吃了牛排
He had steak before both comas.
你弟弟有鸟氨酸氨甲酰转移酶缺乏症[O.T.D.]
Your brother has ornithine transcarbamylase deficiency.
要我写给你看吗
Want me to write it down?
好  因为写下来要花点时间
Good, 'cause it takes a while.
这是遗传疾病  随时有可能发作
It's genetic, can present at any time.
如果病人吃进去大量蛋白质
If the patient eats a large amount of protein,
尤其是他身体不适应的情况下
especially if he's not used to it-
什么  就这样
What, that's it?
他只要不吃红肉就没事了吗
He just stays off the red meat, and he's gonna be fine?
是的  如果我对了现在停止治疗  他就会好起来
Yes. If I'm right and we stop the current treatment, he gets better.
但如果我错了而停止治疗  那他就会死
If we stop the current treatment and I'm wrong, he dies.
-你怎么会错  -他的雌激素水平
- Why would you be wrong? - His estrogen level.
这种病不影响雌激素水平
O.T.D. Doesn't explain his estrogen level.
但是  我有个理论
But I have a theory.
有那么种化学物质  如果摄入人体
There is one chemical that, if ingested,
可能引起雌激素水平急剧上升
can cause a person's estrogen level to increase dramatically.
-是什么  -就叫雌性激素
- What is it? - It's called estrogen.
乔伊使用雌性激素  怎么  他想变性不成
Joey's taking estrogen? What, he wants a sex change?
不  倒不是这个
No, nothing like that.
它叫作"雄性火焰"
It's called "Male Flame."
用中国原话讲可能更好理解
It's probably more consumer-friendly in the original Chinese.
-是一种草本春药  卖给男同志的  -开始扯了
- It's an herbal aphrodisiac marketed to gay men. - Ah, here we go.
卖柴胡糖的同一家网站就有
And it's sold on the same Web site that sells his Chai Hu lozenges.
你猜它成分是什么  "雌"打头的
Guess what's in it? It starts with an "E."
你也找打吗
You wanna get hit too?
这招说不定也很奏效啊
That would be quite a trick.
他狠狠地揍了我  于是他的哥哥变直男了
He slapped me so hard, his brother turned straight.
乔伊是黑帮大佬  像他这样的人在监狱里不会被强暴
Joey's a big-time mobster. Guys like that don't get raped in prison.
大家要讨好他  送礼物  送食物  毒品  香烟
They get gifts. They get food, drugs, cigarettes.
还有电视看
Cable TV.
乔伊不是同志
Joey is not gay.
就算不是同志吧  但肯定相当愉快
Maybe not gay, but certainly delightful.
相反你呢  殴打医生  哪怕只是奇斯
You, on the other hand, hitting a doctor, even if it was only Chase,
而且威胁另一个医生
and asking another one
给乔伊的病例作假不许写他是同志
to keep Joey's chart fresh and homo-free-
这反应有点过头了  你说呢
that's a bit of an overreaction, wouldn't you say?
好像你害怕这是真的
It's almost like you're scared that it might be true.
你错了
You're wrong.
好  那就不要停止治疗
Okay. Then don't stop the treatment.
但如果是你错了  他会死
But if you're wrong, he dies.
好吧
Okay.
他从来没和我说过  一次都没有
He never said anything to me about it, not once.
我就喜欢你们帮派分子这一点  很能宽容他人
That's what I love about you mob guys, so tolerant of others.
很能接受现实
So accepting.
他抽身的唯一办法就是跑得远远的
Only way he was coming out was way, way out.
洗掉纹身  改名换姓  搬到别处去
Lose the tattoos, change his name, move to another town.
可他这样的人怎么会这么做呢
How's a guy like him gonna do that?
证人保护计划
Witness Protection.
不再是仅仅为了证人
It's not just for witnesses anymore.
现在可以进去了  你愿意坐下陪陪他也行
You can go in now, sit with him if you want.
-他还有多久会醒  -才过了三个小时
- How much longer? - It's only been three hours.
-如果是O.T.D.  -什么叫如果是
- If it's the O.T.D. - If it's the O.T.D.?
万一豪斯错了呢
What if House is wrong, huh?
像这么严重的反应  需要时间恢复
That severe a reaction, it'll take some time-
他总是对人做出各种假设  然后说服别人
He makes these assumptions about people, talks you into things-
阿奈罗先生  他醒了  他想见你
Mr. Arnello- He's awake. He wants to see you.
你看起来一团糟
You look like crap.
这是个笑话  听出来没  我生病了  可我说你糟糕
That's a joke. See? I'm sick. I said you look like crap.
你不知道我刚才经历了什么
You have no idea what I just went through out there.
你的病不断加重
You kept gettin' worse.
豪斯医生不断说那些狗屁不通的话
And Dr. House kept sayin' all this crap.
你知不知道  如果我坚持说你正常
You know, if- if I think you're normal,
那他就会继续给你用药
then he's gonna keep giving you the medicine.
-如果你不...  -不什么
- If you weren't- - Weren't what?
不正常
Normal?
是的
Yeah.
他说你是个基佬
He said you were a fag.
证人保护计划  这是你当同志的好机会
Witness Protection- that's your big chance to be one.
-你信了他的话  -我不知道要信什么好
- You believed him? - I don't know what to believe.
你病得那么重
You were sick.
我必须做出决定  我当时以为你快死了
I had to make a decision. I thought you were gonna die.
你相信了他
You believed him.
他停了药
He stopped the medicine.
现在我醒了
Here I am.
-我想和你谈谈这事  -没什么好谈的
- I wanted to talk to you about this. - There's nothin' to talk about.
你...
You, uh,
从网上买了些破中医保健品
ordered some Chinese internet health crap,
结果他们送错药  而你误吃了
and they sent the wrong pills, and you took 'em.
是的  是的  事情...
Yeah, yeah. That, uh-
一定就是这样
That must be it.
你想去作证
You wanna testify?
去吧
Go ahead.
我问过医生了  他说没问题
I told the doc. He said it's okay.
-我不奢望你能理解  -我不理解
- I don't expect you to understand. - I don't.
乔伊  我只需知道你是我兄弟就够了
All I need to know is you're my brother, Joey.
如果你觉得做个...
If you think this...
不管什么  只要能让你开心
thing, whatever, is gonna make you happy,
我就觉得你应该做
then I think you should do it.
你应该去做
You should.
沃格勒要炒你鱿鱼
Vogler wants to fire you.
裁掉整个科室
Lose the whole department.
不过幸好有你为我争取  对吧
Good thing you fought for me though, right?
穿工作服我这一步走得不错  但你得顺势煽风点火
Dress was a nice move, but you gotta follow it up.
维加斯之邪恶周末
Nasty weekend in Vegas.
展示你真正行政能力的时候
Something that shows off your real administrative skills.
他威胁要开除我
He threatened to fire me.
对不起了
I'm sorry.
我还能待多久
So, how long do I have?
我有好多个人物品要收拾
I've got a lot of personal stuff to pack up.
你也要办个欢送会吧
And I assume you're gonna want to throw a party.
我告诉他我知道他的那些肮脏内幕
I told him I know where the bodies are buried.
还有那些他在书本上学不到的本事
The stuff he needs to know that's not in the books.
我叫他别想威胁我
I told him he can't ditch me.
他还留着你
He's only keeping you on
只是因为你知道那些秘密
because you know the secret handshakes.
但他学得快  不消六个月的功夫
He's a quick study. Six months,
等他全部掌握  他就不再需要你了
he'll have the moves down. He won't need you anymore.
-我到时再想办法对付  -那我可以留下
- I'll deal with that then. - So I stay.
是的
Yes.
但一些事情要变一变了
But some things are going to change.
利润  新世界秩序
Profits. New world order.
-一切围绕利润转  -是啊  真新奇
- Everything's about profits. - Yeah, that's real new.
你可以偶尔把你那辆克尔维特租出去
You could rent out the Corvette every once in a while
或者借给朋友
or lend it to a friend.
那很容易  但很不对
That would be easy, and it would be wrong.
可人家卡迪为你挺身而出
But Cuddy stood up for you.
不完全是
To a point.
怎么不完全
To what point?
我每个月要多做六小时门诊  还有他们中的两个
I gotta do six more clinic hours a month. So do two of them.
为什么只有两个
Why only two?
因为有一个要离开这里
'Cause one of them's gone.
我必须炒掉一个人
I gotta fire somebody.
早啊
Good morning.